#前幾天我們去了趟四川
We went to Sichuan in the last few days.
#回來的時候被我弟宰了幾隻竹鼠
Upon getting home, I discovered that my younger brother had slaughtered several bamboo rats.
#我都數了數的
I have counted.
#現在少了兩個
Two bamboo rats are gone.
#現在有一個很胖的
There's a very fat one.
#這個
This one.
#很胖的竹鼠都被他們宰了
He's got a very fat bamboo rat.
#被我
I..
#被我罵了他們一頓
I rewarded them with a bad scold.
#你看 小胖好可愛哦
Look! Small Fatty is very cute,
#一動不動的
just like a statue.
#幸好小胖還在
I'm so glad to see that it's still here.
#我以為小胖被他們宰了
I thought that they got Small Fatty.
#你看 這個那麼聽話的
Look! It's so nice and gentle.
#被他們宰了的話
I would have beaten them up,
#我要揍他們一頓
if they had got Small Fatty.
#你看 多聽話啊 小胖
Look! What a good rat! Small Fatty.
#誒呀 誒呀
Eeya, eeya!
#放回去
Put it back.
#你看 這個 瓜瓜
Look! This is, Gua Gua
#這個
It's
#瓜瓜都那麼瘦了
it becomes so skinny now.
#哇
Wa...
#這個肉質肯定很好吃
The texture of his meat is excellent. He must be very tasty.
#我以為是宰的瓜瓜嘞
I thought it were Gua Gua who was slaughtered.
#原來不是
But it's not him.
#還在
He's still here.
#看一下大胖
Have a look at Big Fatty.
#你看 這個大胖
Look! This is Big Fatty.
#哇 這麼胖
Wa! It's so fat.
#誒呀
Eeya!
#那麼重
It's so heavy.
#拎不住了
I can barely hold it.
#現在胖 大胖都瘦了
Fatty, Big Fatty is now getting thinner.
#你看 本來有五斤多的 現在可能有四斤多
Look! It was almost 3kg, but now it is perhaps slightly more than 2kg.
#那麼重
So heavy!
#有尿
Pee
#看一下西西
Let's have a look at Xi Xi.
#你看 這個西西
Look! This is Xi Xi.
#哇 那麼激動幹嘛
Wa! Why are you so excited?
#誒呦 還想咬我
Eeyo! She wants to bite me.
#現在好乖啦 西西
Xi Xi is now very nice and gentle.
#放回去
Put her back.
#你看它們兩個在幹嘛
See what these two guys are doing!
#不打架啦
Why did you stop fighting?
#繼續打呀
Go on!
#打呀
Fight!
#打完我就燒開水
I'll boil water once you finish fighting.
#好久沒看過小白啦
I have not visited Whitey for a long time.
#小白就在那裡
Whitey is over there.
#前面
This way.
#你看 小白
Look! Whitey!
#給它發了一個黑老婆
I've given him a black wife.
#哇 小白 變胖了
Wa! Whitey! You are getting fat!
#小白
Whitey!
#真的好胖了它
He's really fat.
#現在重了好多
He's much heavier now.
#可能是
Perhaps,
#老婆的原因
it's because of the wives.
#給它發了一個
He now has only one.
#原來是兩個的
But he used to have two.
#現在一個了它就慢慢會胖了
He'll get fat when he has only one.
#也說不定 也說不定
Or perhaps, perhaps,
#秋天
because it's autumn.
#秋天是個 長驃的
autumn is the time for,
#好時候
accumulating fat.
#它頭尖的
He has a sharp head.
#好啦 把你放回去
Alright! I'll put you back.
#你看 這是 我弟他們搞的稻草
Look! This is the straw prepared by our brothers.
#算啦 看他們搞了那麼多稻草的
Well, I'm not going to make a big fuss on them,
#份上
seeing
#不跟他們計較
that they have prepared the straw.
#這是冬
During wint...
#這是竹鼠
the straw becomes
#冬天過冬的 必備的
a necessity of the bamboo rats during winter.
#沒有這個稻草的話 那個
Without the straw,
#小鼠崽啊 或者那個
the baby rats, or, well,
#體質
I mean,
#偏瘦的鼠啊
the skinnier rats,
#那們會那個凍
will get,
#凍感冒的
get a cold.
#好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#我要回家煮飯啦
I need to go home to cook.